Tibet
Marist Archives and Special Collections
- Tibet, 2.1.3.5
  - Tibet: Trip to Dharamsala [Travis L. Fletcher and Katherine Cantwell], circa 1963; 13 (Box 1536)
    - this little Tibetan boy was badly burned in an accident. After care and treatment at the Nursery at Dharamsala by the medical unit of A.E.C.T.R. [American Emergency Committee for Tibetan Refugees] and the Dooley Foundation he is well on the road to recovery. Mr. Thomas saw this little boy shortly after the accident occurred [Katherine Cantwell on left], 5
    - Verso: this little Tibetan boy was badly burned in an accident. After care and treatment at the Nursery at Dharamsala by the medical unit of A.E.C.T.R. [American Emergency Committee for Tibetan Refugees] and the Dooley Foundation he is well on the road to recovery. Mr. Thomas saw this little boy shortly after the accident occurred [Katherine Cantwell on left], 5-verso
    - T.L.F. [Travis L. Fletcher] with a group of children at the Dharamsala nursery. Clothes, shoes, food, blankets and medicines are supplied to this nursery by A.E.C.T.R. [American Emergency Committee for Tibetan Refugees], 6
    - Verso: T.L.F. [Travis L. Fletcher] with a group of children at the Dharamsala nursery. Clothes, shoes, food, blankets and medicines are supplied to this nursery by A.E.C.T.R. [American Emergency Committee for Tibetan Refugees], 6-verso
    - K.K.C. [Katherine Cantwell] and T.L.F. [Travis L. Fletcher] with a group of children at the nursery for Tibetan refugees in Dharamsala. Mrs. Tsering Dolma, sister of the Dalai Lama, stands in the middle between T.L.F. and K.K.C., 7
    - Verso: K.K.C. [Katherine Cantwell] and T.L.F. [Travis L. Fletcher] with a group of children at the nursery for Tibetan refugees in Dharamsala. Mrs. Tsering Dolma, sister of the Dalai Lama, stands in the middle between T.L.F. and K.K.C., 7-verso
    - K.K.C. [Katherine Cantwell] makes friends with one of the many orphans at the nursery at Dharamsala, introduced by Mrs. Tsering Dolma, sister of the Dalai Lama, 8
    - Verso: K.K.C. [Katherine Cantwell] makes friends with one of the many orphans at the nursery at Dharamsala, introduced by Mrs. Tsering Dolma, sister of the Dalai Lama, 8-verso
    - K.K.C. [Katherine Cantwell] and T.L.F. [Travis L. Fletcher] are besieged by large groups of Tibetan refugees during their visits to the various projects, all expressing their gratitude to A.E.C.T.R. [American Emergency Committee for Tibetan Refugees] for the help thus far rendered and pleading for more food, medicines, and clothing, 9
    - Verso: K.K.C. [Katherine Cantwell] and T.L.F. [Travis L. Fletcher] are besieged by large groups of Tibetan refugees during their visits to the various projects, all expressing their gratitude to A.E.C.T.R. [American Emergency Committee for Tibetan Refugees] for the help thus far rendered and pleading for more food, medicines, and clothing, 9-verso
  - Tibet: Trip to Dharamsala, circa 1963; 14 (Box 1536)
    - [Lowell Thomas and four men in Tibet], 1
    - [Lowell Thomas and three men in Tibet], 2
    - [Lowell Thomas and two unidentified men in Tibet], 3
    - [Lowell Thomas and three men standing in a fountain in Tibet], 4
    - [Lowell Thomas and four men in Tibet], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas and three men in Tibet], 6
    - [Lowell Thomas and three men in Tibet], 7
    - [Lowell Thomas and an unidentified man in Tibet], 8
  Box 1537
- Tibet, 2.1.3.5
  - Tibet: Trip to Dharamsala, circa 1963; 1 (Box 1537)
    - [Lowell Thomas and four men in Tibet], 1
    - [Lowell Thomas and three men looking at a map in Tibet], 2
    - [Lowell Thomas pointing at something on a map in Tibet], 3
    - [Lowell Thomas looking at something on a map in Taibet], 4
    - [Building in Tibet], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas and an unidentified man in Tibet], 6
    - [Lowell Thomas and a monk in Tibet], 7
    - [Lowell Thomas and a monk in Tibet], 8
    - [Lowell Thomas and two monks in Tibet], 9
    - [Lowell Thomas and an unidentified man in Tibet], 10
    - [Lowell Thomas and a man in a turban in Tibet], 11
    - [Lowell Thomas exchanging a silk sash in Tibet], 12
    - [Lowell Thomas and a man in Tibet exchanging a silk sash], 13
    - [Lowell Thomas and a man in Tibet], 14
    - [Lowell Thomas and a man in Tibet], 15
    - [Lowell Thomas and an unidentified man in Tibet], 16
    - [Lowell Thomas and a man on the side of the road next to a jeep in Tibet], 17
    - [Lowell Thomas looking at the mountains in Tibet], 18
    - [Mountains in Tibet], 19
    - Landscape in Tibet], 20
    - [Lowell Thomas and three Tibetans dressed in traditional clothing], 21
    - [One man and two women in Tibetan clothing], 22
    - [Group of four in Tibetan clothing], 23
    - [Two men and two women in Tibetan clothing], 24
    - [Group of Tibetans], 25
    - [Group if Tibetans holding a flag], 26
    - [Group of Tibertans holding a flag], 27
    - [Young Tibetans], 28
  - Tibet: Trip to Dharamsala, circa 1963; 2 (Box 1537)
    - [Conference in Tibet], 1
    - [Conference in Tibet], 2
    - [Lowell Thomas receiving a necklace in Tibet], 3
    - [Lowell Thomas giving a speech in Tibet], 4
    - [Lowell Thomas speaking at a conference in Tibet], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas with five others in Tibet], 6
    - [Lowell Thomas receiving a gift in Tibet], 7
    - [Lowell Thomas opening a gift in Tibet], 8
    - [Lowell Thomas admiring his gift in Tibet], 9
    - [Lowell Thomas and two unidentified men in Tibet], 10
    - [Lowell Thomas speaking with a man in Tibet], 11
    - [Lowell Thomas and three others in Tibet], 12
    - [Lowell Thomas speaking with two people in Tibet], 13
    - [Lowell Thomas speaking with three others in Tibet ], 14
    - [Lowell Thomas sitting with three others in Tibet], 15
    - [Lowell Thomas and three others in Tibet], 16
    - [Lowell Thomas and a man in Tibet], 17
  - Tibet: Trip to Dharamsala, circa 1963; 3 (Box 1537)
    - A small group out [of] approximately 5000 Tibetan refugees who were evacuated from NEFA during the recent invasion of India by Communist china. They managed to escape with only the clothes they wore and have since sought refuge in the interior of India, wandering aimlessly, bewildered, disillusioned and discouraged. In this photo are a small group of 2200 who have recently come to Delhi, India in search of help. AECTR [American Emergency Committee for Tibetan Refugees] has donated blankets and food to them, 1
    - Verso: A small group out [of] approximately 5000 Tibetan refugees who were evacuated from NEFA during the recent invasion of India by Communist china. They managed to escape with only the clothes they wore and have since sought refuge in the interior of India, wandering aimlessly, bewildered, disillusioned and discouraged. In this photo are a small group of 2200 who have recently come to Delhi, India in search of help. AECTR [American Emergency Committee for Tibetan Refugees] has donated blankets and food to them, 1-verso
    - Dr. Nallathambi is pictured in consultation with one of scores of patients who queque [queue] up to seek his services daily. This medical project is operated jointly by A.E.C.T.R. [American Emergency Committee for Tibetan Refugees] and the Dr. Dooley Foundation. At Doctor Nallathambi's right is a social worker trained by A.E.C.T.R., another social worker is with the Tibetan nurse and K.K.C. [Katherine Cantwell] to the right in this photograph. This is a good demonstration of how two American agencies may co-operate in rendering a useful service to depressed peoples, 2
    - Verso: Dr. Nallathambi is pictured in consultation with one of scores of patients who queque [queue] up to seek his services daily. This medical project is operated jointly by A.E.C.T.R. [American Emergency Committee for Tibetan Refugees] and the Dr. Dooley Foundation. At Doctor Nallathambi's right is a social worker trained by A.E.C.T.R., another social worker is with the Tibetan nurse and K.K.C. [Katherine Cantwell] to the right in this photograph. This is a good demonstration of how two American agencies may co-operate in rendering a useful service to depressed peoples, 2-verso
    - A distressed and disillusioned Tibetan mother with her child who escaped the Chinese invasion of Assam, India. Presents were distributed to all of the children on the occasion of the Tibetan New Year 1963, 3
    - Verso: A distressed and disillusioned Tibetan mother with her child who escaped the Chinese invasion of Assam, India. Presents were distributed to all of the children on the occasion of the Tibetan New Year 1963, 3-verso
    - A Tibetan refugee receives treatment on a medical project in northern India. The project is operated jointly by AECTR [American Emergency Committee for Tibetan Refugees] and the Dr. Thomas A. Dooley Foundation. In this photo, one of an average of 150 patients who receive treatment daily. Also a Tibetan welfare worker and a Tibetan Nurse, both of them received training by AECTR. Large quantities of medicines have been donated generously y American pharmaceutical firms to AECTR for this and other medical projects, 4
    - Verso: A Tibetan refugee receives treatment on a medical project in northern India. The project is operated jointly by AECTR [American Emergency Committee for Tibetan Refugees] and the Dr. Thomas A. Dooley Foundation. In this photo, one of an average of 150 patients who receive treatment daily. Also a Tibetan welfare worker and a Tibetan Nurse, both of them received training by AECTR. Large quantities of medicines have been donated generously y American pharmaceutical firms to AECTR for this and other medical projects, 4-verso
    - [Tibetan refugees], 5
    - [Two women visiting Tibetan refugees], 6
  - Tibet: Dalai Lama [includes color photographs], circa 1970s; 4 (Box 1537)
    - Dikung Chetsang Rinpche [Rinpoche?] is giving his priestly vow to His Holiness the Dalai La [Lama], at Dhramsalla [Dharamsala] on Sept. 13th 1968, 1
    - Note: Dikung Chetsang Rinpche [Rinpoche?] is giving his priestly vow to His Holiness the Dalai La [Lama], at Dhramsalla [Dharamsala] on Sept. 13th 1968, 2
    - After the ceremony, all participants are served with tea and rice, as a symble [sic] of auspicious rejoicing [1968], 3
    - Note: After the ceremony, all participants are served with tea and rice, as a symble [sic] of auspicious rejoicing [1968], 4
    - His Holiness is giving his final advice to the Rinpoche and bidding farewell with a scarf [1968], 5
    - Note: His Holiness is giving his final advice to the Rinpoche and bidding farewell with a scarf [1968], 6
    - [Lowell Thomas and the Dalai Lama, circa 1970s], 7